A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Office Files of Marian Krauskopf FA515
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Office Files of Marian Krauskopf
1986-1999
Rockefeller Archive Center
Krauskopf, Marian
Ford Foundation
FA515
4.53 Cubic Feet
4.52 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Boxes 1-2 (Part of Accession 2012:018) were transferred to the RAC by the Ford Foundation in 2012. Boxes 3-7 were transferred to the RAC as Accession 2018:087 by the Ford Foundation in 2018.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains Marian Krauskopf's office files, including replication studies, files relating to the Innovations in American Government program, and proposals for the New Leaders in a Changing World.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series:
1. Replication Study, 1986-1997
2. Innovations in American Government, 1995-1998
3. New Leaders in a Changing World, 1994-1999
Biographical / Historical
Marian Krauskopf served as a project specialist within the Asset Building and Community Development unit within the Office of the Vice President at the Ford Foundation until 2003. Later, as consultant to the Foundation, Krauskopf was responsible for coordinating the Leadership for a Changing World, a project to document the work of social change organizations and highlight the importance of community leadership in the US.
- Replication Study, 1986-1997; 1; 1.31 Cubic Feet 1 record storage box
  - 1986 Replication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1987 Replication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1988 Replication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1990 Replication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1991 Replication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1992 Replication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1993 Replication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1994 Replication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1995 Replication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Replication Study Returns, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Replication Data/Write-up and Analysis, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1997 Replication (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Innovations in American Government, 1995-1998; 2; 2.45 Cubic Feet
  - Martin and Glanz Partnerships, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Marian Krauskopf Finalist Events, 1996 September 5-6 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Innovations in American Government Program 10th Anniversary Booklet, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1997 CEO Summit: Rethinking Life and Work, 1997 September 15 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Innovations Meeting Follow-up 4/30 Meeting, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Innovations Strategic Planning, 1998 June 2 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Innovations Retreat, 1998 March 17 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Innovations Strategic Planning Desk File, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Leadership Network of Program Directors, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Replication--Innovations, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Maximizing the Value of Public Sector Innovation, Strategic Computing Telecommunications in the Public Sector and Innovations in American Government, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 23-25)
  - Partnership for Trust in Government and Council Support for the Innovations in American Government Awards, Bi-Monthly Updates, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Media Study - Images of Government in TV Entertainment: Overview, 1998 July (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Innovations in American Government - Winner's Toolkit, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Innovations in American Government - Winner's Toolkit, 1998; 3 1/2 inch floppy disk (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access copy currently unavailable. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
  - Initial Media Coverage - Innovations in American Government Awards (3 folders), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 29, Box 4, Folder 30-31)
  - Innovations in American Government 1997 - Awards Competition Initial Media Report, 1997 October 27 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Innovations in American Government - 1999 Awards Program Round Two (4 folders), 1999 May 12 (Box 4, Folder 33-36)
  - Innovations in American Government - 1998 Program Book (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Innovations in American Government - Finalist Presentations (3 folders), 1998 October 21 (Box 5, Folder 38-40)
  - Innovations in American Government - Finalist Presentations (3 folders), 1998 October 21 (Box 5, Folder 41-43)
- New Leaders in a Changing World, 1994-1999; 3; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes
  - MSK Reviewed Proposal Finalist - MDC, Inc./The Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service, New York University/The Common Enterprise, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - MSK Reviewed Proposed Finalist - Fetzer Institute (2 folders), 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 45-46)
  - Responses to RFP: New Leaders for a Changing World - List of Organizations, 1999 July 20 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Public/Private Ventures Finalist Presentation, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Learning to Love the Swamp: Reshaping Education for Public Service, Ellen Schall, Association for Public Policy Analysis and Management (APPAM), 1994 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Building Communities of Conscience and Conviction, Lessons from Recent Experience, MDC, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - New Leaders for a Changing World - Plans, undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - New Leaders for a Changing World - Program Resources (2 folders), 1995-1999 (Box 6, Folder 52-53)
  - MSK Reviewed Proposed Finalist - Southern Regional Council, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - MSK Reviewed Proposed Finalist - Highlander Research and Education Center, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Proposal - Center for New Readership and Democracy - Rockefeller Foundation, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Proposal - The James MacGregor Burns, Academy of Leadership, University of Maryland (2 folders), 1999 (Box 6, Folder 57-58)
  - Proposal - Eureka Communities, Claremont Graduate University, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Proposal - The Hauser Center for Nonprofit Organizations, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Proposal - Third Sector New England, Heller School for Advanced Studies in Social Welfare, Brandeis University, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Proposal - Tufts University, Lincoln-Filene Center, 1999 July 20 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Proposal - Center for Policy Alternatives, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Proposal - The Africa-America Institute, 1999 July (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Proposal - Ms. Foundation for Women (3 folders), 1999 July (Box 7, Folder 65-67)
  - Proposal - The Academy for Educational Development (AED), 1999 July (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Proposal - Jepson School of Leadership Studies, University of Richmond, 1999 July (Box 7, Folder 69)